{"tossups": [{"question": "Samuel Wyllys was technically the owner of this thing, which received its name from an item that was supposed to be taken at Butler\u2019s Tavern. This thing was killed in an 1856 thunderstorm, and it was immortalized on the fifth-issued state quarter in 1999. In 1687, Joseph Wadsworth prevented Edmund Andros from seizing a poorly-written contract by hiding it in this object. For ten points, name this tree that once held a royal document belonging to Connecticut Colony.", "answer": "<b> Charter Oak</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man dismissed a commissioner who would go on to lead the Army Comrade Association, which sought to prevent physical intimidation by a group supported by this man. This man attempted to reconcile with Richard Mulcahy after fighting broke out at the Four Courts. This man backed a group sometimes known as the \u201cIrregulars\u201d that warred with a faction led by William Cosgrave. When his motion regarding eligibility in the<em> D\u00b4ail If</em> was rejected, this man broke from Sinn F\u00b4ein. For ten points, name this first Taoiseach [TEE-shuh] of Ireland and founder of Fianna F\u00b4ail [fi-anna foil].", "answer": "\u00b4Eamon de<b> Valera</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This event was investigated by a commission headed by the president of Dartmouth, John Kemeny. When this event was politicized by Jane Fonda, Edward Teller wrote a<em> Wall Street Journal</em> article claiming that the heart attack he suffered the next day made him the \u201conly victim of\u201d it. Governor Dick Thornburgh ordered an evacuation within five miles of this event, which was mitigated by the SCRAM emergency protocol when faulty valves caused steam generators to not receive enough water. For ten points, name this Carter-era disaster in which a Pennsylvania reactor went into partial meltdown.", "answer": "<b> Three Mile Island</b> nuclear accident (accept descriptions of the (partial) meltdown at<b> Three Mile Island</b>; prompt on descriptions that don\u2019t name the facility)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 2013, this leader declared that youth should \u201cdare to dream\u201d and \u201ccontribute to the revitalization of the nation.\u201d In 2012, this leader wrote the Eight Point Regulations, which called for making the party \u201ccloser to the masses.\u201d After taking office in 2013, this leader launched a massive anti-corruption campaign, vowing to crack down on the \u201ctigers and flies\u201d and arresting Xu Caihou and Zhou Yongkang. For ten points, name this current Paramount leader of China.", "answer": "<b> Xi</b> Jinping", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "James Conway founded a powerful democratic faction in this state called \u201cThe Family.\u201d In a conflict in this state, a speech by Jack Agery about a fearsome bull led one side to be labeled the \u201cBrindle Tails;\u201dthat Reconstruction-era conflict arose after disputes over an 1872 gubernatorial election and was known as the Brooks-Baxter War. In a Civil War battle in this state, Samuel Curtis defeated Earl Van Dorn at Pea Ridge. For ten points, name this state where railroad construction led to immigration to the southern Ozarks and which was the site of Civil War action in cities like Hot Springs and Little Rock.", "answer": "<b> Arkansas</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man, who names the main stadium at Flushing Meadows, once said \u201cAIDS killed my body, but racism is harder to bear.\u201d For ten points, name this African-American tennis star who died in 1993.", "answer": "Arthur Robert<b> Ashe</b>, Jr", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "The remnants of this group surrendered after their headquarters were raided by the American 71st Division in Austria, shortly after it was reconstituted as the \u201cOstmark\u201d organization. This group was split into \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d designations to launch a two pronged strike in a grab for the Baku oil fields during Operation Blue. Hermann Hoth\u2019s 4th Panzer Army was transferred to this group shortly before it lost Friedrich Paulus\u2019 Sixth Army at Stalingrad. For ten points, name this German army group that pushed into the Ukraine and the Caucasus on the onset of Operation Barbarossa.", "answer": "Army Group<b> South</b> (accept Army Group<b> Ostmark</b> before mentioned) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Michael Riccardi stabbed this man in the chest in a failed assassination attempt after this man led demonstrations in Bensonhurst after the killing of Yusef Hawkins. This host of the radio show<em> Keepin\u2019It Real</em> led an anti-Semitic march during the 1991 Crown Heights Riot. At the age of nine, this man was ordained as a Pentecostal Minister, though he later became a Baptist. For ten points, name this African-American civil rights activist and pastor from New York.", "answer": "Alfred Charles \u201cAl\u201d<b> Sharpton</b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A conjecture that this mathematician names with Petersson claims that his namesake tau function of p is less than or equal to two times p to the eleven-halves power. This man found many formulae for q-series and mock theta functions that were published in 1987 as part of his \u201cLost Notebook.\u201d This mathematician told his advisor that his taxicab number, 1729, is the smallest integer that can be written as the sum of two different pairs of perfect cubes. For ten points, name this Indian mathematician, a prominent colleague of G.H. Hardy, the subject of<em> The Man Who Knew Infinity</em>.", "answer": "Srinivasa<b> Ramanujan</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {}, {"question": "Javad Fakoori ordered a failed surprise attack against this country in which four Phantom jets tried to carry out Operation Scorched Sword; the French helped repair the damage from that attack. David Ivry helped plan another attack on this country that provided the first application of Menachim Begin\u2019s foreign doctrine; in announcing that doctrine, Begin noted that \u201clater may be too late.\u201d That attack on this country was codenamed Operation Opera and carried out by the Israeli Air Force through Saudi airspace to prevent this country from developing nuclear weapons. For ten points, name this country that tried to build a nuclear reactor south of Baghdad.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Iraq</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this international pact of 1928 that renounced war as an \u201cinstrument of national policy\u201d and is named after two diplomats.", "answer": "<b> Kellogg-Briand</b> Pact (accept<b> Pact of Paris</b>; accept<b> General Treaty for Renunciation of War as an Instrument of National Policy</b> before \u201crenounced\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This group\u2019s Robert McBride was sentenced to death after detonating an explosive at the Magoo Bar. This group targeted Amanzitomi and Church Street in a series of bombings, actions that were found to be excessive by the Truth and Reconciliation Commission. This paramilitary group, which was created to avenge the Sharpeville Massacre, was led by a man who declared that he was \u201cprepared to die\u201d during the Rivonia Trial. For ten points, name this militant wing of the African National Congress, co-founded by Nelson Mandela.", "answer": "<b> Spear of the Nation</b> (or<b> uMkhonto we Sizwe</b>; accept<b> MK</b>; prompt on Spear; prompt on African National Congress or ANC before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "He spent almost all of that time in exile in London.", "answer": "Oliver<b> Tambo</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This province is home to Smallwood Reservoir, which was created to service the world\u2019s second-largest underground hydropower station. In 1934, high debts forced this province to give up its status as a self-governing dominion. This province is home to Churchill Falls, and a plateau to its southeast known as the Grand Banks was home to a cod fishery that collapsed in 1992. For ten points, what easternmost province of Canada consists of a namesake island and the mainland portion of Labrador?", "answer": "<b> Newfoundland</b> and Labrador", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "These people were led by a man named Garson in the defense of the Negro Fort. Escaped slaves who fled to this tribe were known as their \u201cBlack\u201d variant, and this tribe reneged on the coerced Treaty of Payne\u2019s Landing. Two British \u201cagents\u201d were hung in 1818 during a controversial campaign against the Creek and this tribe. Some members of this tribe, led by Osceola, fled deep into the Everglades rather than admit defeat after one of its three wars with the United States. For ten points, name this Native American tribe attacked by Andrew Jackson in early 19th century Florida.", "answer": "<b> Seminole</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "An electrician named Platyev is claimed to have hit the perpetrator of this event in the face with a screwdriver. The day after this event, Borisov was killed after being thrown from a truck. This event may have been planned by Vania Zaporozhets. Lev Kamenev and Grigory Zinoviev were convicted of providing moral support for this event, which was perpetrated by Leonid Nikolayev in the Smolny. For ten points, name this December 1934 death of the Leningrad Party Boss, used by Stalin to initiate the first of his great purges.", "answer": "<b> Assassination</b> (or<b> murder</b>,<b> killing</b>, etc.) of Sergei<b> Kirov</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man presided over Stalin\u2019s Great Purge, then was purged himself; a common example of Stalin\u2019s \u201cerasing\u201d of the past is this man\u2019s disappearance from a picture of the Moscow Canal.", "answer": "Nikolai<b> Yezhov</b> <b></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Muhammad Hadi continued writing a memoir that this author stopped working on at the age 17. This emperor, who became drinking partners with ambassador Thomas Roe,</b> <b>ordered the arrest of Guru (+)</b> <b>Arjan Dev, who was executed when he refused to convert</b> <b>to Islam. This man blinded his son Khusrau after an attempted revolt, and he himself unsuccessfully revolted against his (*)</b> father while the latter was fighting in the Deccan Plateau in 1599. For ten points, name this fourth Mughal emperor, the son of Akbar.", "answer": "<b> Jahangir</b> (or Mirza Nur-ud-din Beig Mohammad Khan<b> Salim</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Rejected names for this state included Vandalia and one named after a river formed by the confluence of the New and Gauley Rivers. This state\u2019s Logan County was the site of a labor clash between Bill Blizzard and Don Chafin, the Battle of (+) Blair Mountain. A 2006 explosion near the Buckhannon River here killed twelve workers at the Sago Coal Mine. Kanawha was first proposed as the name for this state, whose first capital was located in its (*) </b> northern panhandle along the Ohio River. Wheeling is found in, for ten points, what Appalachian state that broke away from its eastern neighbor during the Civil War?", "answer": "<b> West Virginia</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>After substitution was made permanent rather than temporary, this price was the new cost for hiring a substitute to go in one\u2019s place in the Union Army. George McGovern publicly claimed that he would back his running mate Thomas Eagleton [this number] (+) percent, but privately pressured him to withdraw in favor of Sargent Shriver. In a war that lasted this many days, Theodore Roosevelt sent gunboats to support Panamanian independence from Colombia. George (*)</b> Herbert Walker Bush, in speaking at the 1988 Republican National Convention, described volunteer organizations as this many \u201cpoints of light.\u201d For ten points, give this number that, as noted by Ronald Reagan in a debate with Jimmy Carter, is how many billions are in a trillion.", "answer": "one<b> thousand</b> (accept $<b>1000</b>,<b> Thousand</b> Days War and equivalents,<b> 1000</b> percent,<b> thousand </b>points of light)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In an attack on this man\u2019s work, Innocent Gentillet blamed this man for causing the St. Bartholomew\u2019s Day Massacre. Voltaire edited and attempted to suppress a work by</b> <b>Frederick the Great attacking this man, who drew some of his ideas from the (+)</b> <b>Orti</b> <b>Oricellari, and Rousseau argued that this man satirized one-man rule in a work that often appears with his made-up biography of Castruccio Castracane. This man idolized (*)</b> Cesare Borgia in a work that claims it is better to be feared than loved. For ten points, name this Florentine thinker, who wrote<em> The Prince</em>.", "answer": "Niccol\u00b4o<b> Machiavelli</b> Page 11", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 334 BC, Alexander the Great nearly lost a siege of this city, but he prevailed over Memnon of Rhodes and restored Ada to the throne of Caria. This city, which succeeded Mylasa as the capital of the Hecatomnids, was the birthplace of (+) Herodotus. A queen of this city was said to make the men of Xerxes look like women at the battle of Salamis. The (*)</b> burial ground of a Persian satrap and Artemisia II in this city gave rise to a word that refers to a building used as a tomb. For ten points, name this ancient Greek city whose Mausoleum was a Wonder of the World.", "answer": "<b> Halicarnassus</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}